Gaze
This is... the footage from CCTV cameras that happened to capture the FBI agents who died in Japan on film.
以上が、日本で亡くなった FBI 捜査官を…
偶然監視カメラが捉えていた影像です
This is... the footage from CCTV cameras that happened to capture the FBI agents who died in Japan on film.
Show me the following scenes involving Ray Penber one more time: him at the ticket barrier, boarding the train, and his death scene, please.
レイ．ペンバーの改札のシーン、
乗車のシーン、そして死のシーンだけを、
もう一度三つ並べて見せてください
Okay...
はい
Err...
えっと…
It's just under there.
その下です
Oh, you mean these?
ああ、これか
Let's see... Ray Penber arrived at Shinjuku station via the west entrance at 15:11. At 15:13, he boards the Yamanote line.
えっと…レイ．ペンバーは
十五時十一分、新宿西口の改札から入っています
Let's see... Ray Penber arrived at Shinjuku station via the west entrance at 15:11. At 15:13, he boards the Yamanote line.
十五時十三分、山手線に乗車、誰かを尾行していたとしても、
Even if he was following someone, it's difficult to tell due to the fuzzy images.
この不鮮明な影像からは、
それを割り出すのは困難かと思われます
And then at 16:42... huh? Ah, thank you!
そして十六時四十二分…
あ、ありがとうございます
Err.. and then at 16:42, he died on the platform at Tokyo station.
えっと…そして、十六時四十二分、
東京駅ホームにて死亡です
Err.. and then at 16:42, he died on the platform at Tokyo station.
Just as I thought; it's odd.
やはり変ですね
Huh?
What's odd, L?
何が変なんだ L
Have you figured something out?!
何か気づいたんですか？
Judging from this footage, from the time he boarded and the time he died, Ray Penber was on the train for an hour and a half. The Yamanote line only takes an hour.
今の話だと、レイ．ペンバーは乗車して死ぬまで、
一周一時間の山手線に一時間半乗っていたことになる
The important thing to note here is the envelope.
そして何より封筒です
Envelope?
封筒？
Both by the ticket barrier and on the platform, he seems to be carrying an envelope or something similar.
改札とホームでは、封筒らしき物を手にしている
Oh, y-you're right!
お…確かに
He does, he does!
持ってます持ってます
But in the moments preceding his death... it vanished.
死の直前の影像では…消えてる
Great job on noticing that, Ryuuzaki!
よくこんなのに気付きましたね竜崎
There's nothing that fits that description in the lost property lists.
遺留品リストに封筒に見えるような物は無い
In that case, it must have been inside the train.
では電車の中ということになる
And in this final video of Penber... it looks to me as if he's frantically trying to see inside the train.
それとこのペンバーの最後のビデオ
私には、
必死に電車の中を見ようとしてるように見えるのですが…
And in this final video of Penber... it looks to me as if he's frantically trying to see inside the train.
Is it possible that it's a hint?
もしそうならそこにヒントは…
If that was Kira, don't you think it'd be interesting?
キラだったら面白いじゃないですか
I-It can't be?!
な…まさか
I doubt it too.
私もまさかとは思います
If Kira is able to manipulate deaths from a distance, they wouldn't bother coming to the scene.
遠隔で死を操れるキラがわざわざ現場にいるはずがない
But if that's what we're supposed to believe, they may have done something extremely daring here.
しかし、そう考えるであろうことを逆手にとって
大胆な行動に出たのかもしれません
But if that's what we're supposed to believe, they may have done something extremely daring here.
You okay, Light?
大丈夫か、ライト
You've been continuously writing criminals' names into the Death Note for four days now, and you've barely slept.
もう四日もろくに寝ずに、
デスノートに犯罪者の名前を書き続けているぞ
Why'd ya need to schedule deaths up to four weeks in advance?
何でそんな何週間も
先まで死のスケジュールを組む必要があるんだ？
簡単に言えば、僕が入院したりしたら？
Basically, if I ever end up in a hospital or something, people won't be able to say, "the instant Police Chief Yagami's son was hospitalized, the killings stopped".
「夜神局長の息子さんが入院した途端、
犯罪者が死ななくなりましたね」って事になるだろ？
Oh, right. I got ya.
そういうことか…
More importantly, are you certain that it's fine to write these on a date before the actual date of death?
そんなことより、
本当に寿命が来る前の日付なら、大丈夫なんだろうな
Shinigami don't use it in such a way, so I can't say for certain; but logically, writing it before the date of death should be fine.
死神はそんな使い方しないから絶対とは言い切れないが、
理屈から言って、寿命より前なら大丈夫だろう
Shinigami don't use it in such a way, so I can't say for certain; but logically, writing it before the date of death should be fine.
You're so unreliable.
当てにならないな…
That's right!
ならないよ
Yes... yes... please hold.
はい
はい、少々お待ちください
Ryuuzaki, it's Ukita-san at the Police Headquarters.
竜崎、警察庁の宇生田さんが、
気になる一般情報の電話を、今受けているとのことですが…
Ryuuzaki, it's Ukita-san at the Police Headquarters.
He says he's received an interesting call from a member of the public.
In that case, pass them the number to phone five, and tell them to call that instead.
あ…では、五番の番号を向こうに教え、
その情報者にそこに掛け直すようにと伝えてもらって下さい
Matsuda-san, you can turn on your cell phone... no... I meant please switch it on now.
松田さん、携帯の電源入れていいですよ
いや、入れてください
Matsuda-san, you can turn on your cell phone... no... I meant please switch it on now.
あ、はい
Okay.
あぁ…！
Hello, head of Kira Incident Public Information Hot-line, Suzuki speaking.
はい、こちらキラ事件特別一般情報主任の鈴木で～す
Ray Penber's fiancée?
レイ．ペンバーの婚約者？
Misora Naomi... where have I heard that name before...
南空ナオミ…
どこかで聞いた名だな
Misora Naomi... where have I heard that name before...
It's her... from the Los Angeles BB serial killer case.
彼女か…
ロサンゼルス BB 殺人事件の…
It's her... from the Los Angeles BB serial killer case.
I see... the girl who worked for me on that case... in Japan...
そうか…
あの事件私の元で働いてくれた彼女が日本に…
She disappeared a few days after her fiancé died.
フィアンセの死の翌日から、彼女も消息が判らないそうです
Anyone would be depressed if their fiancé just died.
フィアンセが死んだら、誰だって落ち込む
まさか…
She wouldn't have... committed suicide?!
…自殺
No. The Misora Naomi that I knew was strong of heart and a brilliant FBI investigator.
いや、私の知っている南空ナオミは、
芯の強い優秀な FBI 捜査官です
If anything, she would have been trying to catch Kira.
むしろ、キラを捕まえる事を考えるはず
彼女はペンバーと一緒にいたそうです、
Apparently she was with Penber.
She might have discovered something...
何かを掴んだのかもしれない
So, does this mean that Kira beat me to it?
だとしたら…キラに先を越されたのか…
Everyone. From now on, we'll only be investigating those who were under surveillance by Ray Penber.
皆さん、これよりレイ．ペンバーが日本で
調べていたものだけに限って捜査します
Everyone. From now on, we'll only be investigating those who were under surveillance by Ray Penber.
The subjects of our investigation will be two police officers and their immediate family.
捜査対象は…二人の警察関係者とその周辺…
Who are the two police officers?
誰なんです、その二人と言うのは…
Deputy Kitamura and his family, and.. Chief Yagami and his family.
北村次長とその家族、
そして…夜神局長とその家族です
Deputy Kitamura and his family, and.. Chief Yagami and his family.
そしてその二つの家に、
I'd also like to be able to set up cameras and bugging devices in both households.
盗聴器と監視カメラをつけさせて頂きたい
I've got to ensure that if anyone ever checks this PC it won't give me away.
このパソコンも、誰が調べても大丈夫にしておく必要がある
Now, all that's left is to hide a piece of the Death Note somewhere...
後はデスノートの切れ端を仕込んでおけば…
You know, you've got some pretty skilled hands there.
しかし、手先も器用だな
I bet that makes you popular with the ladies, Light.
女にモテるだろうライト
It's got nothing to do with having skilled hands.
器用さなんて関係ないよ、器用より器量だ
It's more about looks rather than skill.
Why, Ryuk? Don't the girls go for you?
もしかしてリューク、モテないのか？
Surveillance cameras! Ryuuzaki?!
監視カメラって、竜崎！
That's out of the question.
いくらなんてもそれは無理ですよ
バレたら人権問題になり、私たちも皆クビに…
If it gets out, it'll become a civil liberties issue; we'll all be fired!
I thought that we would put our lives on the line here, not just our jobs.
クビどころか命まで掛けて私たちは捜査していたはずです
Ryuuzaki, what's the probability of Kira being among them?
竜崎、その中にキラがいる可能性は…
10%... No, 5%.
１０パーセント…
いや、５パーセントです
10%... No, 5%.
You're going to do all that based on just a 5% probability?
そんな、たった五パーでそこまで…
いや、今までの捜査では、
怪しいと思える者すらいなかったんだ…
Up until now, we haven't encountered anyone even remotely suspicious.
Even if there is just a 1% probability, it's worth investigating it thoroughly.
１パーセントでも可能性があるなら、とことん調べるべきだ
Chief!
局長…
私も自分の家族を疑われていたのでは心外だ
I regret that my own family falls under suspicion.
いいでしょう、つけてください
Very well, please set it up.
In exchange, I'd like the whole house covered; from the bathroom to the toilet. I don't want to find a single place overlooked!
その代わり家の隅々、
バスルームからトイレまで見落としのないようにだ…
In exchange, I'd like the whole house covered; from the bathroom to the toilet. I don't want to find a single place overlooked!
ありがとうございます、そのつもりです
Thank you. I intend to.
Chief! What are you saying?!
きょ、局長…何を言ってるんですか
He's right! You've got a wife and daughter!
そうですよ、局長には奥さんや娘さんもいるんですよ
I realize that! I know what I'm saying.
判ってるって言ってるんだ！
However, if we don't do this thoroughly, then there's no point in doing it at all!
やるなら徹底的にやらなければ意味のないことも…
Just shut it!
お黙っていてくれ！
Sorry...
すみません…
No, it's fine.
いや、いいんだ…すまん
I'm sorry.
Well, the least I can do is to have only Yagami-san and myself carry out the surveillance of his family.
ではせめてもの配慮として
夜神家の官舎が私と夜神さんのみで行いましょう
Watari, how long will it take to set up surveillance cameras and monitors?
ワタリ、盗聴器カメラモニターの設置にどれくらいかかる？
Once we know the times during which each of the houses will be vacant, we can set them up any time from tomorrow onwards.
明日以降であれば…
両家の不在時間が判れば、いつでも取り付けられます
See ya, Light.
じゃあな、月
Yeah, see you tomorrow.
ああ、また明日な
Huh? Nobody is home?
なんだ、誰もいないのか？
I'm home.
ただいま
Hey, Light, doesn't seem like anyone is home; it's been a while, so how about we play some video games?
なあ、ライト、家に誰もいないようだし、
久しぶりに、二人でゲームしない？
Hey, Light... let's play some games.
なあ、ライト、ゲームだよ
You listening?
聞いてる？
Light?
…ライト？
I-I had no idea... that he was doing something like that!
ま…まさか、あんなことをしてるなんて…
Has he got something in his room that he doesn't want anyone to see?
部屋に何か見られたくない物でもあるのか…
If you take into account that he's seventeen, it's nothing to be that suspicious about.
十七歳ということを考えたら、
そんなに怪しむことではありません
I've done that myself in the past for no particular reason.
私も意味なくやったことがあります
Have you spoken to him about the investigation?
彼に捜査状況を話したことは…
Don't be stupid!
馬鹿な…報道されない極秘事項は絶対話しはしない
I would never discuss un-released, top-secret information!
Besides, I'm hardly ever at home, and when I am, I'm usually tired, so I go straight to bed.
それに、最近はろくに帰ってもいないし、
帰っても疲れて、眠るだけだ
Besides, I'm hardly ever at home, and when I am, I'm usually tired, so I go straight to bed.
I see...
…わかりました
Where you going, Light?
どこへ行くんだライト
Hey, Light! Why are you ignoring me? I'm starting to feel a little pissed here...
おい、ライト、さっきから無視しやがって怒るぞ
Hey, Light.
おい、ライト
It doesn't appear to be any bugs in these clothes.
この服に盗聴器は仕込まれていない…
Light-ooo!
ライト…
リューク、家に監視カメラか盗聴器、
Ryuk, it's possible that surveillance cameras or bugs no, probably both... have been set up in my house.
いや多分両方だろう、仕掛けられている可能性がある
Huh? But that piece of paper in your door was still there...
あれ、でも、ドアに紙切れ挟まってたじゃないか
あの紙は…僕が部屋に誰が入ったか
確かめてると思わせる為のフェイクだ
That bit of paper is merely a decoy to fool people into thinking that that's how I tell if someone has been in my room.
In reality, the first clue is the door knob.
実際はまずドアノブ…
The door knob?
ドアノブ？
When that door closes, the handle naturally returns to a horizontal state.
あのドアノブは、ドアを閉めると水平の位置に自然にあがる、
それ以上はあがらない
It's impossible for it to go any higher.
However, when I close the door, I always purposely lower the handle 5mm from it's highest point.
しかし僕はいつもドアを閉めた後、
わざと一番上まで上がった位置から、
また五ミリほど下げている
Thus, when I go to open the door, if the door knob is all the way up, there's the possibility that someone has been in my room.
つまりドアを開ける時、
ノブが上がりきっていたら…誰かが部屋に入った可能性がある
Thus, when I go to open the door, if the door knob is all the way up, there's the possibility that someone has been in my room.
But I can't determine that for sure with just that piece of information.
ただそれだけでは人が入ったと決め付けられない
That's why I've set up a piece of mechanical pencil lead as well.
だからシャープペンの芯も仕掛けておいた
Piece of mechanical pencil lead?
シャーペンの芯？
It's by the hinge.
蝶番だよ、ドアを閉めた後、蝶番の上に、
I've placed it on the top of the hinge at such an angle that it'll break if the door is opened.
ドアを開けると折れる角度で、シャープペンの芯を挟んでいる
The lead will definitely break if the door has been opened.
ドアを開かれば必ず芯は折れる、
Normally, I remove it myself before I enter the room, but today it was already broken.
今までは自分で抜いて入っていたか今日は折れていた…
Oh, that? I remember you setting that up.
おお、あれか、やってたな
ドアノブと芯…誰かが入ったのはまず間違いない
The door knob and the piece of lead... Without a doubt, someone has definitely been in there.
It could have been your parents?
親じゃないのか？
If it was my parents, or even my sister, they wouldn't have noticed that piece of paper.
親や妹なら紙にすら気付かない
It's suspicious because the piece of paper was replaced.
紙をわざわざ元に戻してるからこそ怪しいんだ
Welcome!
いらっしゃいませ
You buying books so that you can swat up on wiretapping and surveillance?
おいおい、今から盗聴や盗撮の本買って勉強する気か
Now that I think about it, Ryuk, what's going to happen with your apples?
ところでリューク、リンゴはどうなる？
Apples?
リンゴ？
Ah! If you saw it through a surveillance camera, it wouldn't be visible once I'd eaten it, but until then, it would look as though it was floating in mid-air!
あ…監視カメラを通して見たら
オレの口に入ってしまえばリンゴは見えないが、
持ってる時は宙に浮いて見えるな
やっぱり…死神は死なないから餓死もしない…
Just as I thought.
Shinigami can't die, so you aren't going to starve to death.
つまりリンゴをあげなくても問題はないな
There won't be any problems with not giving them to you, right?
W-Wait a second, Light.
ちょ、ちょっと待ってくれライト
For me, apples are like... Let's see... it's like alcohol and tobacco are for some humans.
俺にとってのリンゴっていうのは、そ…そうだな、
人間でいう酒やタバコみたいな物で、
ずっとないと禁断症状が…
If I go without them for a long time, I'll get withdrawal symptoms.
What kind of symptoms?
どんな症状が出るんだ？
My body will start contorting randomly, or I'll start doing handstands...
体を無茶苦茶にひねたり…逆立ちしたり
I'd rather not see that.
見たくないな…
Right?!
だろう
Listen up, Ryuk. I've already given L the hint that "Shinigami only eat apples."
いいかリューク、
そうじゃなくても僕は、
「死神はリンゴしか食べない」と、 L にヒントを与えてある
When did you--?
いつの間に？
If you really want to eat apples, you'll first need to memorize the positions of all the cameras.
どうしてもリンゴが食べたかったら…
まず全てのカメラの位置を把握する
If you really want to eat apples, you'll first need to memorize the positions of all the cameras.
もしかしたら、リンゴを食べる死角くらいあるかもしれない…
There may be an angle from which you can safely eat your apples.
Okay, let's go, Ryuk!
じゃあいくよ、リューク
Okay, here goes the camera search!
おお、カメラ探し
This could be fun too!
これもまた面白、なはぁ…
お…いや、オレはカメラを探さないと…
Wait... I was supposed to be searching for cameras...
あ、あの真面目な息子があんな雑誌を…
I can't believe that my son, who's so serious, would go and look at those sorts of magazines.
That's normal for a 17-year-old.
十七歳なら普通です
が、私には…
But to me, it seems as though he's using it as some kind of excuse, i.e. "I check to see if anyone has been in my room because I read dirty magazines".
「部屋に誰か入っていないか確かめていたのは、
こういう本があるからです」
っと言い訳しているように見えるんです
Ryuuzaki, don't tell me, you actually suspect my son?!
ま…まさか竜崎、
うちの息子を疑っているのか…
Oh, I definitely suspect him, alright.
疑ってますよ
That's the reason I set up cameras and wires in you and the deputy's houses.
だからお宅と次長の家に、盗聴器とカメラをつけたんですから
ん？
I've found a camera within the air conditioner!
エアコンの中にカメラ発見
So, I was right; there are cameras.
やはりカメラはついていたか…
That means they must have wired the place as well.
となると盗聴器もだろう…
Even if it's for the sake of the Kira investigation, I doubt that the Japanese police would go this far.
いくらキラ捜査の為とは言え、
日本警察がここまでやるとは思えない…
Is it possible that L instigated this?
L の差し金か…だとしたらどこまで絞られている
If so, how many people have they narrowed it down to?
If they haven't narrowed it down to just the people that were being investigated by Ray Penber, it's doubtful that they would take these measures so far.
最低でも、レイ．ペンバーが調べていた
者の内の誰かまで絞っていなかれば…
ここまではしない
Argh, I've been tricked by the cover again.
はあぁ～、また表紙に騙された
No! In these circumstances, it's best that I imagine that I'm the only one under surveillance and act accordingly.
いや…こういう時は、
僕だけが疑われ監視されていると考えて、行動すべきだ
It's okay. I've even prepared magazines such as this especially for such an occasion.
大丈夫、こういう事態に備えて、
こんな本まで色々準備してきたんだ…
Light...
月…
Onii-chan, it's dinner time!
お兄ちゃん～、ご～はん～だよ
I... love you.
君を…愛してる…
はぁ…
Wow! You're so cool, Ryuuga Hideki!
いや～～♥
素敵すぎるよ流河旱樹
Wow! You're so cool, Ryuuga Hideki!
There's definitely no one this cool in my class!
クラスにはいないよね、絶対
Sayu! Eat your dinner!
粧裕、ご飯食べちゃいなさい
Later.
あとで
Aizawa-san, are the Kitamura family watching TV right now?
相沢さん、北村家は今テレビ見てますか？
Yes. Except for the deputy, they're all watching while eating dinner.
はい、次長除く四人で、食事をしながら見てます
They're watching channel four.
四チャンネルです
ワタリ、各テレビ局に例のテロップを流すように指示してくれ
Watari, quickly contact the TV station, and ask them to broadcast that tape.
Understood.
わかりました
That's right, I've...
NKK News Flash
The ICPO have decided to send 1,500 investigators from the most developed nations into Japan to assist with the Kira case.
Huh? What's this?
え、なに
The ICPO have decided to send 1,500 investigators from the most developed nations into Japan to assist with the Kira case?
ICPO は、キラ事件に対し先進各国から総勢1500人の
捜査員を日本に派遣する事に決定…
The ICPO have decided to send 1,500 investigators from the most developed nations into Japan to assist with the Kira case.
1500人だって、すごっ
1,500 people! Wow.
There should be cameras in here too.
このリビングにもカメラはついているはず…
「このニュースが本当であろうとなかろうと、
これを見せて反応を見よう」ということか…
It doesn't matter whether that piece of news is real or not, all they want to do is to see what my reaction is.
L, you're using the same trick that you used at the beginning.
L …最初の時と手口が同じだ
That's really stupid of the ICPO.
馬鹿だな、 ICPO も
Huh?!
え？
There's no point in making an announcement like that.
こんな発表をしたら意味がない
If they are going to send in investigators, they should do it quietly.
送り込むならこっそり入れ、こっそり捜査させるべきだ
Even the FBI, who were investigating in the utmost secrecy were killed.
極秘で捜査した FBI でさえ、あんな目に遭ったのに、
This is just going to be a repeat of what's already happened.
これじゃその二の舞になる
だからこれは、大げさに報道してキラを動揺させようという警察の作戦さ
So this is probably a plan by the police to unnerve Kira by broadcasting it in such an exaggerated manner.
But I think it'd be fairly obvious to Kira.
でもこれじゃキラにもバレバレじゃないのかな
Your son is very clever.
賢いですね、息子さん
Yes... well...
で…うん、まぁ…
Thanks for the meal.
ごちそうさま
Onii-chan! You're eating potato chips after dinner?!
きゃ…お兄ちゃんご飯あとにポテチ？
Your cool style will go to waste if you get fat!
せっかくスタイルいいのに太るよ
It's a late night snack to aid me with my studies.
受験勉強の夜食だよ
L-Light... I've found all the cameras.
ラ…ライト、カメラ全部探し出したぜ
死神も頑張ると疲れるんだな…
Even Shinigami get tired if they work so hard.
I'll explain it now.
今から説明するぞ
ちょっと大変だからよく頭に入れてくれ
It's rather complicated, so make sure you get it all.
I don't want to explain it again.
二度説明するのはごめんだからな
よし、頑張るぞ勉強
Okay, time to study hard!
There's a hell of a lot of cameras.
物凄いカメラの数だ、
つけた奴は見つかるの覚悟でつけてるとしか思えない
I can only imagine that whoever placed them here was prepared to be caught if necessary.
There's 64 in total.
全部で六十四個だ
Just as I thought, this is L's work.
やっぱり L だ…
Just like the time he blithely allowed a condemned criminal to call me out the first time; I can see that he knows no limits.
宣戦布告の時に、死刑囚を椅子に平気で座らせたり…
奴も限度って物を知らない…
In such circumstances, where can I eat my apples?
で、この状態で、オレどこでリンゴ食うの？
It's impossible of course, Ryuk.
無理に決まってるだろ、リューク
I forgot... we can't talk inside the house.
家の中じゃ喋れないんだったな…
明日外に出た時教えてくれ
Let me know tomorrow when we get outside.
オッケー、この問題も正解
Okay. This problem is correct.
Judging by the positions and number of cameras present, it looks as though they want to get this over with within a few days.
カメラの数とつけ方から考えて、
短期間で見極めるつもりらしいな…
Judging by the positions and number of cameras present, it looks as though they want to get this over with within a few days.
A normal person may slip up within this period, but it won't be that easy, L.
普通の人間ならこれでボロを出すだろうが…
そうはいかないよ、 L
A normal person may slip up within this period, but it won't be that easy, L.
そこまでだ！
This is as far as it goes!
I've already scheduled deaths up to three and a half week in advance in the Death Note, but L already knows that Kira can manipulate the time of death.
三週間先まで犯罪者は死んでいくように
デスノートにも記してあるが…
I've already scheduled deaths up to three and a half week in advance in the Death Note, but L already knows that Kira can manipulate the time of death.
キラは死の時間を操れるということも L には示している
In that case, criminals will need to continue to die while he can see that I'm not watching any new broadcasts containing their information.
だからこの場合、僕が何の情報も得ていない時に…
新しく報道される犯罪者が死んでいけばいい…
Oh, crap! The withdrawal symptoms are starting to kick in...
まずい、禁断症状が…
I'll show you, L!
やってやるよ、 L ！
Thanks to Ryuk's information, and the preparations I made earlier, I can convince everyone that I'm nothing but a hard-working exam student,
リュークの情報と前もっての仕込みで…
どう見ても勉強している受験生を装いながら…
僕はデスノートで、今報道されている犯罪者を…
And at the same time, while information on the criminals is still being broadcast, I can use the Death Note... to kill them!
殺すことが出来る
Using my right hand to continue solving problems, I can use my left hand to write names... and to take out chips to eat.
右手で方程式を解き続け…
左手で名前を書き
Using my right hand to continue solving problems, I can use my left hand to write names... and to take out chips to eat.
ポテチを取り…食べる！
After dinner, without switching on the TV or the PC, your son studies continuously.
夕飯の後、息子さんはテレビもパソコンもつけず、
ずっと勉強ですね
It's less than ten days to the exams.
センター試験まで十日きりましたがら
And now a criminal, whom I could never have known about, will die of a heart attack in forty seconds.
これで僕の知り得なかった犯罪者が四十秒後には心臓麻痺…
僕のアリバイの目撃者は L 本人だ
L himself will be the witness to my alibi.
Right, just a little more!
よし、もうひと頑張り
Ryuuzaki.
竜崎
What's up, Watari?
どうした、ワタリ
Two criminals just reported on tonight's nine o'clock news... a bank employee under investigation for embezzlement,
先程、今日九時のニュースで初めて報道された、
横領容疑の銀行員が取調べ中に…
and a bag-snatching thief being held in police custody... both died earlier from heart attacks.
そして、引ったくり犯が留置場で、
二人とも、心臓麻痺で亡くなりました
キラだ！
It's Kira!
At that time, your wife and daughter were watching a soap opera.
夜神さんの宅はその時間、奥さんと娘さんはドラマを見ていた
When that finished, they switched off the TV and haven't watched it since.
ドラマが終わるとテレビを消し、その後は一切見ていない
Your son has been studying from 19:30 till now.
息子さんは七時半過ぎから
十一時現在まで勉強しかしていない…
Kira needs a name and a face in order to kill.
キラは殺人に顔と名前が必要…
"Anybody who wasn't watching that news broadcast can't be Kira?"
そのニュースを見ていなかったものはキラではない、か…
うちの家族は、これで潔白ですね
That must mean my family is innocent!
Today, Kira seems to have gone for extremely minor criminals immediately after their information was released.
今日のキラは、随分罪の軽いものを、
報道されてすぐに殺しましたね
And the Yagami household seems entirely too innocent on the first day of surveillance...
そしてカメラをつけて初日だというのに、
夜神家は面白いほどすんなり白だ…
Light! Are you up yet?!
月、起きてるの？
Yeah, I'm up!
ああ、起きてるよ
Today is garbage collection day, so if you have any, bring it down.
今日ゴミの日だから、あるなら出してね
What a bother...
面倒くさいな…
What are you on about?
何言ってるの
それぐらい言われなくてもって、いつはいってるでしょ？
You're always telling me that you don't need to be told.
Yes, yes...
はいはい
The weather looks good again.
今日もいい天気だ
You really don't care what you have to do to get this job done, do ya?
しかし、
自分の為なら手段を選ばないというか、気前がいいというか
Either that, or you're extremely generous...
あの小型液晶テレビ、三万九千八百円だろ？
That small TV cost you 39,800 yen, didn't it?
Good morning!
おはようございま～す
To be continued
これはいい…何を悲観することはない
これは向こうも何も掴んでいない証拠だ…
アイツも僕もじかに接しての騙し合い
知恵比べだ